JERRY HUANG

💌 jerryhuang@utexas.edu 🔇 jerryhuang.ca 📞 956-624-6912 (USA) | 647-720-0497 (CAN) 🕠 jerryhuang3

SUMMARY

Full-stack web developer and fast learner who is comfortable working in teamoriented and solo environments. With an educational background in film and business, I have plenty of experience working in collaborative environments requiring small teams. My experience in the e-commerce business has taught me how to self-learn and run a successful business with little to no direction or experience.

I have always loved computers and have built over 10 personal desktops in my life. Prior to the web development bootcamp I took a course on C++ and Fortran which piqued my interest in this field. Finding new joy the field of programming, I am ready to improve my skills as best as I can.

EDUCATION

The University of Texas at Austin · 2009 - 2013

BS Radio TV Film

Ted Rogers School of Management ·

2017 - 2020

MBA Management of Innovation and Technology

Lighthouse Labs ·

Mar. 2019 - May 2019 Web Development Bootcamp

SKILLS

LANGUAGES: Javascript, Ruby,

HTML, CSS

FRAMEWORKS/LIBRARIES:

Node, React, Express, Ember, Ruby on Rails, Webpack, Parcel, Bootstrap, Foundation, Knex, Sass, EJS

DATABASES/SYSTEMS:

PostgreSQL, MongoDB

PLATFORMS/TOOLS: Heroku,

Netlify, Git

EMPLOYMENT

Far Eastern International Inc

Hidalgo, TX, Retail and Sales Manager

Jan. 2014 - Aug. 2018

- Generated \$300K in revenue first year
- Worked with domestic and international suppliers and manufacturers to produce or procure new products
- Increased sales up to > 60K units yearly with revenues of \$750K for 2016
- Planned inventory budgets, implemented marketing strategies, and monitored
- Created efficient strategies to minimize and respond to customer complaints
- Researched trends of products and analyzed competitor operations to determine consumer demand

Northpark Distributors

Austin, TX, Co-founder

July 2018 - Current

- International distribution service
- Manage freight and logistics of imported products from China to US

PROJECTS

Shlack - https://github.com/jerryhuang3/shlack

Sept. 2019

High performance Slack clone built with Ember Octane using server side rendering.

Petfinder - https://petfinder.netlify.com

Aug. 2019

Pet adoption app using Petfinder.com API. Built with React, Parcel, and Reach Router.

Buffering - https://github.com/jerryhuang3/buffering

May 2019

Fitness tracking application with Chrome extension that degrades user internet experience if fitness goals are not met. OAuth integration with Google Fit API.

tinyJungle - https://github.com/jerryhuang3/tinyJungle

Apr. 2019

E-Commerce application using Stripe for payments and built with Ruby on Rails.

tinyChatr - https://tinychatr.herokuapp.com

Web application built with Node, React, and Webpack that enables users to chat and send images to each other.

Walmark - https://walmark.herokuapp.com

Walmark is a user curated, resource wall that can help users organize and bookmark links. Built with Node, Express, Foundation, and PostgreSQL

tinyTweet - https://tinytweeter.herokuapp.com

Mar. 2019

Single page Twitter clone built with Node, Express, and MongoDB

tinyApp - https://lighthouselabs-tinyapp.herokuapp.com

Mar. 2019

Web application built with Node and Express that allows users to shorten long URLs

AWARDS

2nd Place. MBA Games

National Competition amongst MBA schools in academic case competitions, athletics, and spirit.